	var quizArray = [{
		"id":"0",
		"question":"___________are the only planets that rotate clockwise (retrograde rotation.)",
		"choice1":"Mercury and Venus",
		"choice2":"Venus and Uranus",
		"choice3":"Earth and Pluto",
		"choice4":"Earth and Uranus",
		"correct":"Venus and Uranus"
	},
	{
		"id":"1",
		"question":"All ___ of Uranus moons are named after William Shakespeare and Alexander Pope characters.",
		"choice1":"28",
		"choice2":"27",
		"choice3":"29",
		"choice4":"26",
		"correct":"27"
	},
	{
		"id":"2",
		"question":"Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and _______ are made up of just gas with no solid surface to land on.",
		"choice1":"Earth",
		"choice2":"Neptune",
		"choice3":"Mercury",
		"choice4":"Mars",
		"correct":"Neptune"
	},
	{
		"id":"3",
		"question":"The angular sizes of the Moon and Sun as seen from Earth are both about 0.5 degrees. The Sun is about 400 times farther away than the Moon. From this we can conclude that the Moon’s diameter is ——- the Sun’s diameter.",
		"choice1":"nearly the same as ",
		"choice2":"about 2 times smaller than ",
		"choice3":"about 400 times smaller than",
		"choice4":"about 2 times larger than",
		"correct":"about 2 times larger than"
	},
	{
		"id":"4",
		"question":"A ”light-year” can be defined as",
		"choice1":"the distance that light travels during the time that Earth revolves around Sun once.",
		"choice2":"the distance between Sun and the nearest star.",
		"choice3":"the distance that Earth travels in one year as it orbits Sun once.",
		"choice4":"the time required for light to travel between Earth and Sun.",
		"correct":"the distance that light travels during the time that Earth revolves around Sun once."
	},
	{
		"id":"5",
		"question":"When does the new moon set?",
		"choice1":"at sunset",
		"choice2":"at noon",
		"choice3":" it never rises",
		"choice4":"at midnight",
		"correct":"at sunset"
	},
	{
		"id":"6",
		"question":"Why does the scientific community prefer to use the metric system over the system (e.g., feet and miles) we normallyuse in our everyday lives?",
		"choice1":"The metric system is more accurate.",
		"choice2":"The metric system can deal with larger numbers than the other system, and astronomy always deals with large numbers.",
		"choice3":"The metric system allows for much easier calculations.",
		"choice4":"None of the above. The scientific community does not prefer to use the metric system because everything in.",
		"correct":"The metric system allows for much easier calculations."
	},
	{
		"id":"7",
		"question":" If the Sun were a grapefruit in this room, the nearest star (Proxima Centauri) would be _____",
		"choice1":"more-or-less another grapefruit on the West Coast.",
		"choice2":"a poppyseed about 15 m away.",
		"choice3":"a peppercorn about 100 m away.",
		"choice4":"more-or-less another grapefruit on the other side of campus.",
		"correct":"more-or-less another grapefruit on the West Coast."
	},
	{
		"id":"8",
		"question":"The difference between radiation and sound is that ____",
		"choice1":"radiation has wavelength and frequency, whereas sound does not.",
		"choice2":" sound needs a physical medium through which to travel, whereas radiation does not.",
		"choice3":" radiation travels much slower than sound.",
		"choice4":"radiation travels at different speed, depending on wavelength, whereas sound always travels at the same",
		"correct":"radiation has wavelength and frequency, whereas sound does not."
	},
	{
		"id":"9",
		"question":"The principle use of dividing the sky up into constellations today is to",
		"choice1":"identify regions and/or designate positions for objects in the sky.",
		"choice2":"allow historians to recall and/or identify the ancient gods and goddesses.",
		"choice3":"establish the basis for the retelling of mythological stories of the stars.",
		"choice4":"allow astrologers to predict the future.",
		"correct":"identify regions and/or designate positions for objects in the sky."
	},
	{
		"id":"10",
		"question":"For mapping purposes, the Earth is divided into two equal halves by an imaginary line called the equator. Likewise, the sky is divided into two equal halves by an imaginary line called the",
		"choice1":"celestial equator",
		"choice2":"ecliptic",
		"choice3":" line of nodes",
		"choice4":"zodiac",
		"correct":"celestial equator"
	},
	{
		"id":"11",
		"question":"Absolute zero is",
		"choice1":"zero degrees Celsius",
		"choice2":"the temperature at which water freezes",
		"choice3":"the temperature at which atoms have no remaining energy from which we can extract heat",
		"choice4":"both a and b",
		"correct":"the temperature at which atoms have no remaining energy from which we can extract heat"
	},
	{
		"id":"12",
		"question":"In the hydrogen atom, the electron and proton are bound together by",
		"choice1":"gravitational force",
		"choice2":"nuclear force",
		"choice3":"electromagnetic force",
		"choice4":"chemical force",
		"correct":"electromagnetic force"
	},
	{
		"id":"13",
		"question":"Each day, from a point on Earth just south of the equator, most stars appear to remain stationary overhead.",
		"choice1":"remain stationary overhead.",
		"choice2":"rise in the east and set in the west",
		"choice3":"move to the north",
		"choice4":"rise in the west and set in the east",
		"correct":"rise in the east and set in the west"
	},
	{
		"id":"14",
		"question":"A hydrogen atom making a direct transition from an upper energy level to the ground (lowest) energy level emits a photon which has an energy which depends on the temperature of the atom",
		"choice1":"emits a photon with an energy exactly equal to the difference in energy between the two states",
		"choice2":"experiences a Doppler shift",
		"choice3":"absorbs a photon which has an energy which depends on the temperature of the atom",
		"choice4":" emits a continuous spectrum.",
		"correct":"emits a photon with an energy exactly equal to the difference in energy between the two states"
	},
	{
		"id":"15",
		"question":"Blackbody radiation is",
		"choice1":"due to the thermal motion of electrons, which emit photons",
		"choice2":"continuous (lineless) in its energy spectrum",
		"choice3":" invisible to the naked eye",
		"choice4":"continuous (lineless) in its energy spectrum",
		"correct":"due to the thermal motion of electrons, which emit photons"
	},
	{
		"id":"16",
		"question":"If the Earth suddenly reveresed its direction of spin, without changing its orbital direction around the Sun_____",
		"choice1":"the Sun would rise in the West and set in the East",
		"choice2":"the stars would move across the sky counterclockwise around Polaris",
		"choice3":"over the year the Sun would travel in reverse through the signs of the Zodiac compared to now",
		"choice4":"over the year the Sun would travel in reverse through the signs of the Zodiac compared to now",
		"correct":"the Sun would rise in the West and set in the East"
	},
	{
		"id":"17",
		"question":"Which of the following statements about radiation is TRUE?",
		"choice1":"Ice cubes at a temperature below the freezing point do not emit black body radiation.",
		"choice2":"Solid objects emit radiation. Objects composed of gases do not.",
		"choice3":"The maximum intensity of radiation emitted by a human body is at infrared wavelengths.",
		"choice4":"Hot objects emit less short wavelength radiation than do cooler objects.",
		"correct":"The maximum intensity of radiation emitted by a human body is at infrared wavelengths."
	},
	{
		"id":"18",
		"question":"What causes seasons here on planet Earth?",
		"choice1":"The tilt of the Earth’s axis.",
		"choice2":"Periodic changes in the heat retention of the Earth’s atmosphere",
		"choice3":"The elliptical orbit of the Moon.",
		"choice4":"Because of the alignment of the solar and lunar cycles.",
		"correct":"The tilt of the Earth’s axis."
	},
	{
		"id":"19",
		"question":"Newton concluded that some force had to act on the Moon because ______.",
		"choice1":"a force is needed to keep the Moon in motion",
		"choice2":" a force is needed to pull the Moon outward",
		"choice3":" the Moon moved at a constant velocity",
		"choice4":"a force is needed to pull the Moon away from straight-line motion",
		"correct":"a force is needed to pull the Moon away from straight-line motion"
	},
	{
		"id":"20",
		"question":"From smallest to largest, what is the correct order of the following distances? (ly stands for light year)",
		"choice1":"1 cm, 1 km, 1 ly, 1 AU",
		"choice2":"1 km, 1 AU, 1 cm, 1 ly",
		"choice3":" 1 AU, 1 ly, 1 cm, 1 km",
		"choice4":"1 cm, 1 km, 1 AU, 1 ly",
		"correct":"1 cm, 1 km, 1 AU, 1 ly"
	},
	{
		"id":"21",
		"question":"All planetary orbits are",
		"choice1":"circles with the Sun at the center",
		"choice2":"circles with the Sun at one focus",
		"choice3":"ellipses with the Sun at the center",
		"choice4":"ellipses with the Sun at one focus",
		"correct":"ellipses with the Sun at one focus"
	},
	{
		"id":"22",
		"question":"The sun is",
		"choice1":"a star",
		"choice2":"1 AU from Earth",
		"choice3":" more than 100 times the diameter of Earth",
		"choice4":"none of the above",
		"correct":"none of the above"
	},
	{
		"id":"23",
		"question":"A red ball is red because",
		"choice1":"it only emits frequencies corresponding to red",
		"choice2":"it only reflects frequencies corresponding to red",
		"choice3":"it only transmits frequencies corresponding to red",
		"choice4":"it only absorbs frequencies corresponding to red",
		"correct":"it only reflects frequencies corresponding to red"
	},
	{
		"id":"24",
		"question":"What phase would the Earth appear to be in if you were standing on the Moon at Full Moon?",
		"choice1":"New",
		"choice2":"Cresent",
		"choice3":"Moon phase",
		"choice4":"Quarter",
		"correct":"New"
	},
	{
		"id":"25",
		"question":"From smallest to largest, the correct order of the following objects is ____",
		"choice1":"Earth’s orbit, Jupiter, Milky Way Galaxy, Solar System",
		"choice2":"Earth’s orbit, Milky Way Galaxy, Solar System, Jupiter",
		"choice3":"Earth’s orbit, Milky Way Galaxy, Solar System, Jupiter",
		"choice4":"Solar System, Earth’s orbit, Milky Way Galaxy, Jupiter",
		"correct":"Earth’s orbit, Jupiter, Milky Way Galaxy, Solar System"
	},
	{
		"id":"26",
		"question":"The principle difference between radio waves and visible light is ___",
		"choice1":"radio waves travel at the speed of sound",
		"choice2":"radio waves carry substantially more energy per photon",
		"choice3":"only visible light can travel through the vacuum of space",
		"choice4":"radio waves have a longer wavelength than visible light",
		"correct":"radio waves have a longer wavelength than visible light"
	},
	{
		"id":"27",
		"question":"An astronaut has a mass of 60 kilograms before she takes off in her ship. When she reaches Earth orbit, her mass is ________________, when she lands on the Moon, her mass is ____________.",
		"choice1":"zero, smaller than on Earth",
		"choice2":"much smaller than on Earth, smaller than on Earth",
		"choice3":"zero, the same as on Earth",
		"choice4":"the same as on Earth; the same as on Earth",
		"correct":"the same as on Earth; the same as on Earth"
	},
	{
		"id":"28",
		"question":"The circular shape of the Earth’s shadow on the Moon led early astronomers to conclude that",
		"choice1":"the Earth is a sphere",
		"choice2":"the Earth is at the center of the Solar system",
		"choice3":"the Earth must be at rest",
		"choice4":"the Earth must be at rest",
		"correct":"the Earth is a sphere"
	},
	{
		"id":"29",
		"question":"If light takes 8 minutes to reach the earth from the sun and 5 hours to reach Pluto, what is the distance from the sun to Pluto?",
		"choice1":" 5 AU",
		"choice2":"37.5 AU",
		"choice3":"37.5 ly",
		"choice4":"5 ly",
		"correct":"37.5 AU"
	},
	{
		"id":"30",
		"question":"The sun is on the celestial equator at the times of",
		"choice1":"the vernal equinox and the summer solstice",
		"choice2":"the autumnal equinox and the vernal equinox",
		"choice3":"the summer solstice and the winter solstice",
		"choice4":"the autumnal equinox and the winter solstice",
		"correct":"the autumnal equinox and the vernal equinox"
	},
	{
		"id":"31",
		"question":"If the Moon were two times closer to the Earth, the gravitational force between them would be _______",
		"choice1":"0 B. 1/4 as strong",
		"choice2":"half as strong ",
		"choice3":"twice as strong",
		"choice4":"4 times as strong",
		"correct":"4 times as strong"
	},
	{
		"id":"32",
		"question":"The of a gas is a measure of the average speed of the particles in the gas.",
		"choice1":"heat",
		"choice2":"composition",
		"choice3":"temperature",
		"choice4":"blue shift",
		"correct":"temperature"
	},
	{
		"id":"33",
		"question":"Which of the following radiation has wavelengths that are longer than visible light?",
		"choice1":"Gamma-rays",
		"choice2":"Ultraviolet light",
		"choice3":"Infrared radiation",
		"choice4":"X-rays",
		"correct":"Infrared radiation"
	},
	{
		"id":"34",
		"question":"As a black body is cooled the wavelength of maximum intensity will",
		"choice1":"decrease",
		"choice2":"increase",
		"choice3":"stay the same, but the frequency will decrease",
		"choice4":"none of the above is true",
		"correct":"increase"
	},
	{
		"id":"35",
		"question":"The terms speed and velocity are popularly used interchangeably, but Newton made an important distinction. How does speed differ from velocity?",
		"choice1":"Speed is in miles per hour, while velocity is in kilometers per hour.",
		"choice2":"Speed involves a direction of motion, while velocity involves only the size of the change in position per unit time.",
		"choice3":"Velocity adds a directional component to the speed.",
		"choice4":"first and second choice",
		"correct":"Velocity adds a directional component to the speed."
	},
	{
		"id":"36",
		"question":"An atom can be excited",
		"choice1":"if it emits a photon",
		"choice2":" if it collides with another atom or electron",
		"choice3":"first and third above",
		"choice4":"f it absorbs a photon",
		"correct":"first and third above"
	},
	{
		"id":"37",
		"question":"If the Earth were tipped 35_ instead of 23.5_, seasons on Earth would be",
		"choice1":"hotter in the northern hemisphere, colder in the southern",
		"choice2":"much shorter",
		"choice3":"much less severe",
		"choice4":"much more severe",
		"correct":"much more severe"
	},
	{
		"id":"38",
		"question":"You can view a total lunar eclipse if the Moon is in",
		"choice1":"Moon’s penumbra",
		"choice2":"the Earth’s umbra",
		"choice3":"the Moon’s umbra ",
		"choice4":"the Earth’s umbrella",
		"correct":"the Earth’s umbra"
	},
	{
		"id":"39",
		"question":"The Sun appears in front of a different constellation each month due to the",
		"choice1":"the Earth’s rotation on its axis",
		"choice2":"the Earth’s orbital motion around the Sun",
		"choice3":"the Sun’s motion around the center of the Milky Way Galaxy",
		"choice4":"precession of the rotation axis of the Earth",
		"correct":"the Earth’s orbital motion around the Sun"
	},
	{
		"id":"40",
		"question":"High (spring) tide during the New Moon occurs at",
		"choice1":"Midnight",
		"choice2":"6pm",
		"choice3":"Midnight and Noon",
		"choice4":"Noon",
		"correct":"Midnight and Noon"
	},
	{
		"id":"41",
		"question":"The Copernican model of the universe was important because it",
		"choice1":"was a heliocentric model.",
		"choice2":"contained epicycles.",
		"choice3":"included elliptical orbits.",
		"choice4":"made very accurate predictions for the positions of the planets.",
		"correct":"was a heliocentric model."
	},
	{
		"id":"42",
		"question":"As Moon revolves around Earth once, it rotates",
		"choice1":"once",
		"choice2":"about 29 times",
		"choice3":"24 times",
		"choice4":"365 times",
		"correct":"once"
	},
	{
		"id":"43",
		"question":"Each day, the Moon rises about",
		"choice1":"the same time",
		"choice2":"an hour later",
		"choice3":"It depends on the year",
		"choice4":"an hour earlier",
		"correct":"an hour later"
	},
	{
		"id":"44",
		"question":"Ocean tides are caused primarily by",
		"choice1":"seismic pressure waves beneath the surface",
		"choice2":"tectonic motion of the spreading ocean floor.",
		"choice3":"the Moon’s gravitational pull",
		"choice4":"sunlight reflecting off waves",
		"correct":"the Moon’s gravitational pull"
	},
	{
		"id":"45",
		"question":"If an atom absorbs a photon,",
		"choice1":"other photons summing to the same total energy may later be emitted.",
		"choice2":"the photon must have the right energy for the atom’s energy levels.",
		"choice3":"the atom will gain energy.",
		"choice4":"all of the above",
		"correct":"all of the above"
	},
	{
		"id":"46",
		"question":"A beam of light from a laser has a wavelength of 600 nm, what is the frequency of this light?",
		"choice1":"5 x 1014 Hz",
		"choice2":"6000 Hz",
		"choice3":"3 x 108 m/s",
		"choice4":"2 x 10−15 Hz",
		"correct":"5 x 1014 Hz"
	},
	{
		"id":"47",
		"question":"A lunar eclipse could never occur",
		"choice1":"at high tide.",
		"choice2":"at Spring tide.",
		"choice3":"at Neap tide.",
		"choice4":"within a couple of weeks of a solar eclipse.",
		"correct":"at Neap tide."
	},
	{
		"id":"48",
		"question":"According to Kepler’s laws, a planet moves fastest in its orbit when",
		"choice1":"it is closest to Earth.",
		"choice2":"it is closest to the Sun.",
		"choice3":"it is undergoing a retrograde loop.",
		"choice4":"it first rises at night.",
		"correct":"it is closest to the Sun."
	},
	{
		"id":"49",
		"question":"An object moving around in a perfect circle at a constant speed",
		"choice1":"is experiencing a force.",
		"choice2":"is not accelerating.",
		"choice3":"also has a constant velocity.",
		"choice4":"must also be rotating.",
		"correct":"is experiencing a force."
	},
	{
		"id":"50",
		"question":"Which of the following properties causes an object to experience a gravitational force?",
		"choice1":"being in a magnetic field",
		"choice2":"undergoing rotation",
		"choice3":"experiencing pressure from an atmosphere (or other gases)",
		"choice4":"having mass",
		"correct":"having mass"
		
	}	,
	{
		"id":"51",
		"question":"A rocket blasts propellant out of its thrusters and ”lifts off,” heading into space. What provided the force to lift the rocket?",
		"choice1":"The propellant pushing against air molecules in the atmosphere.",
		"choice2":"The propellant heating and expanding the air beneath the rocket, and so pushing the rocket up",
		"choice3":"The action of the propellant accelerating down, giving a reaction force to the rocket.",
		"choice4":"The propellant reversing direction as it strikes the ground below the rocket, then bouncing back and pushing the rocket up",
		"correct":"The action of the propellant accelerating down, giving a reaction force to the rocket."
	},
	{
		"id":"52",
		"question":" If you apply the same force to two carts, the first with a mass of 100 kg, the second 50 kg, the acceleration of the 100 kg cart will be —— the acceleration of the 50 kg cart.",
		"choice1":"the same as",
		"choice2":"2 times larger than",
		"choice3":"2 times smaller than",
		"choice4":"50 times larger than",
		"correct":"2 times smaller than"
	},
	{
		"id":"53",
		"question":"A spring tide occurs whenever",
		"choice1":"the Earth is closest to the Sun in its orbit.",
		"choice2":"the Moon is in the springtime constellations of the Zodiac.",
		"choice3":"the Moon is full or new.",
		"choice4":"the Sun crosses the celestial equator.",
		"correct":"the Moon is full or new."
	},
	{
		"id":"54",
		"question":"If the net force on an object doubles, then its —– also doubles.",
		"choice1":"acceleration",
		"choice2":"speed",
		"choice3":"mass",
		"choice4":"velocity",
		"correct":"acceleration"
	},
	{
		"id":"55",
		"question":"An object emitting a ”black body” spectrum emits over a broad range of wavelengths, but with a peak which depends on its",
		"choice1":"absorption lines",
		"choice2":"color",
		"choice3":"temperature",
		"choice4":"radius",
		"correct":"temperature"
	},
	{
		"id":"56",
		"question":"When a photon interacts with an atom, what changes occur in the atom?",
		"choice1":"The photon becomes trapped in orbit.",
		"choice2":"An electron changes its orbital.",
		"choice3":"The atomic number increases.",
		"choice4":"The mass of the nucleus increases.",
		"correct":"An electron changes its orbital."
	},
	{
		"id":"57",
		"question":"Object A has a temperature of 200 degrees Kelvin, whereas object B has that of 600 degrees.",
		"choice1":"Object B emits 3 times more radiation than object A.",
		"choice2":"Object B emits 9 times more radiation than object A.",
		"choice3":"Object B emits 27 times more radiation than object A.",
		"choice4":"Object B emits 81 times more radiation than object A.",
		"correct":"Object B emits 81 times more radiation than object A."
	},
	{
		"id":"58",
		"question":"Several times on Star Trek, Mr. Spock fired his phaser at a rock to heat it when he was trapped on a cold planet.Suppose Mr. Spock increased the temperature of a rock to 3 times its initial value. The rock’s black body luminosity would increase",
		"choice1":"3 times",
		"choice2":"6 times",
		"choice3":"9 times",
		"choice4":"81 times",
		"correct":"81 times"
	},
	{
		"id":"59",
		"question":"The entire surface area of Pluto is smaller than what country?",
		"choice1":"Russia",
		"choice2":"Africa",
		"choice3":"Philippines",
		"choice4":"Ireland",
		"correct":"Russia"
	},
	{
		"id":"60",
		"question":"The coldest known place in the universe.",
		"choice1":"Albedo",
		"choice2":"Boomerang Nebula",
		"choice3":"Galaxy",
		"choice4":"None",
		"correct":"Boomerang Nebula"
	},
	{
		"id":"61",
		"question":"The Moon is moving away from the Earth ___cm every year.",
		"choice1":"2.2",
		"choice2":"3.8",
		"choice3":"4",
		"choice4":"4.8",
		"correct":"3.8"
	},
	{
		"id":"62",
		"question":"After helium and hydrogen what is the most common element on the Sun?",
		"choice1":"Oxygen",
		"choice2":"Carbon dioxide",
		"choice3":"Nitrogen",
		"choice4":"Phosphorous",
		"correct":"Oxygen"
	},
	{
		"id":"63",
		"question":"What is the windiest planet in the Solar System?",
		"choice1":"Neptune",
		"choice2":"Pluto",
		"choice3":"Venus",
		"choice4":"Earth",
		"correct":"Neptune"
	},
	{
		"id":"64",
		"question":"The largest moon in the Solar System even bigger than planet Mercury.",
		"choice1":"Active galaxy",
		"choice2":"Jupiter's Ganymede",
		"choice3":"Teldrad",
		"choice4":"Terra",
		"correct":"Jupiter's Ganymede"
	},
	{
		"id":"65",
		"question":"The largest known star 2000 times bigger than the Sun.",
		"choice1":"Neptune",
		"choice2":"Westerlund 1-26",
		"choice3":"Nebula",
		"choice4":"Northern 1-26",
		"correct":"Westerlund 1-26"
	},
	{
		"id":"66",
		"question":"The Moon is moving away from the Earth ___cm every year.",
		"choice1":"Century",
		"choice2":"Dark Matter",
		"choice3":"Sidereal period",
		"choice4":"Shepherd Moon",
		"correct":"Dark Matter"
	},
	{
		"id":"67",
		"question":"The nearest star to us after the Sun.",
		"choice1":"Nebula",
		"choice2":"Centauri",
		"choice3":"Dark Matter",
		"choice4":"Proxima Centauri",
		"correct":"Proxima Centauri"
	},
	{
		"id":"68",
		"question":"The star that dims every 27 years due to a mysterious dark object eclipsing it periodically.",
		"choice1":"Epsilon Aurigae",
		"choice2":"Asteroid",
		"choice3":"Sun",
		"choice4":"Blazar",
		"correct":"Epsilon Aurigae"
	},
	{
		"id":"69",
		"question":"There are three ___balls on the Moon (left by Apollo 14 astronaut Alan Shepard in 1971.",
		"choice1":"basketball",
		"choice2":"golf",
		"choice3":"pong",
		"choice4":"tennis",
		"correct":"golf"
	},
	{
		"id":"70",
		"question":"95% of all matter in the universe is invisible, and is called the ________.",
		"choice1":"Blazar",
		"choice2":"Dark Matter",
		"choice3":"Black hole",
		"choice4":"Catena",
		"correct":"Dark Matter"
	},
	{
		"id":"71",
		"question":"Storm on Jupiter that has been going on for 300 years - is so big that dozens of Earths would fit into it.",
		"choice1":"Great Red Spot",
		"choice2":"Comet",
		"choice3":"Eclipse",
		"choice4":"Jupiter’s Gynemede",
		"correct":"Great Red Spot"
	},
	{
		"id":"72",
		"question":"A _______ is believed to be present in the centre of nearly every galaxy, including our own Milky Way.",
		"choice1":"Ecliptic",
		"choice2":"Finder",
		"choice3":"supermassive blackhole",
		"choice4":"blackhole",
		"correct":"supermassive blackhole"
	},
	{
		"id":"73",
		"question":"Everything moves: Planets move within the Solar System, which moves within Milky Way Galaxy, which moves within The Local Group of Galaxies, which moves towards _____.",
		"choice1":"Gegenschein",
		"choice2":"Ice",
		"choice3":"Virgo Cluster",
		"choice4":"Inferior Planet",
		"correct":"Virgo Cluster"
	},
	{
		"id":"74",
		"question":"________ is not complete vacuum: there are a few hydrogen atoms per cubic centimetre.",
		"choice1":"Galaxy",
		"choice2":"Space",
		"choice3":"Milky Way",
		"choice4":"Interstellar space",
		"correct":"Interstellar space"
	},
	{
		"id":"75",
		"question":"Saturn's moon _____has hundreds of times more oil and natural gas than all the known reserves on Earth.",
		"choice1":"titan",
		"choice2":"spot",
		"choice3":"ring",
		"choice4":"phase",
		"correct":"titan"
	},
	{
		"id":"76",
		"question":"26.	The largest of modern constellations.",
		"choice1":"Hydra",
		"choice2":"Dipper",
		"choice3":"Capricorn",
		"choice4":"Orion",
		"correct":"Hydra"
	},
	{
		"id":"77",
		"question":"27.	The only planet in our solar system not named after a Roman or Greek god.",
		"choice1":"Pluto",
		"choice2":"Earth",
		"choice3":"Mercury",
		"choice4":"Saturn",
		"correct":"Earth"
	},
	{
		"id":"78",
		"question":"24.	Mars is red because____",
		"choice1":"full of red soil",
		"choice2":"due to the sun",
		"choice3":"it's soil is filthy",
		"choice4":"its’ soil is very rusty",
		"correct":"its’ soil is very rusty"
	},
	{
		"id":"79",
		"question":"23.	The most luminous star known - 10 million times the power of the Sun and as big as the size of Earth's entire orbit around the Sun.",
		"choice1":"Pistol Star",
		"choice2":"Gloria",
		"choice3":"Dipper",
		"choice4":"Dark Star",
		"correct":"Pistol Star"
	},
	{
		"id":"80",
		"question":"The largest known star _______is so big that if our Sun were a ball 117 cm (46 in) wide, this star would be 2.25 kilometres (1.3 miles) wide.",
		"choice1":"Canis Majoris",
		"choice2":"Luther",
		"choice3":"Canis Minoris",
		"choice4":"Orion",
		"correct":"Canis Majoris"
	},
	{
		"id":"81",
		"question":"What are comets often called?",
		"choice1":"Dirty Snowballs",
		"choice2":"Silly Streakers",
		"choice3":"Filthy dirty balls",
		"choice4":"Fire Balls",
		"correct":"Dirty Snowballs"
	},
	{
		"id":"82",
		"question":"What organization is responsible for naming constellations?",
		"choice1":"The friendly staff of SPACE.com ",
		"choice2":"Sky and Telescope Magazine",
		"choice3":"The International Astronomical Union",
		"choice4":"None",
		"correct":"The International Astronomical Union"
	},
	{
		"id":"83",
		"question":"An Astronaut can be up to 2 ______ taller returning from space. The cartilage disks in the spine expand in the absence of gravity. ",
		"choice1":"inches",
		"choice2":"cm",
		"choice3":"feet",
		"choice4":"meter",
		"correct":"inches"
	},
	{
		"id":"84",
		"question":"82.	The Earth weighs 6.6 sextillion tons, or _________",
		"choice1":"5.97 x 1024 kg",
		"choice2":"4.97 x 1024 kg",
		"choice3":"3.97 x 1024 kg",
		"choice4":"5.97 x 1124 kg",
		"correct":"5.97 x 1024 kg"
	},
	{
		"id":"85",
		"question":"The Earth orbits the sun at an average speed of ________",
		"choice1":"107,220 km/h",
		"choice2":"127,220 km/h",
		"choice3":"117,220 km/h",
		"choice4":"107,120 km/h",
		"correct":"107,220 km/h"
	},
	{
		"id":"86",
		"question":"A large sunspot can last for about how many weeks?. ",
		"choice1":"one",
		"choice2":"two",
		"choice3":"three",
		"choice4":"four",
		"correct":"one"
	},
	{
		"id":"87",
		"question":"The largest volcano in our Solar System, almost three times taller than Mount Everest on Earth.",
		"choice1":"Olympus Mons on Mars",
		"choice2":"Olympus Mons on Saturn",
		"choice3":"Olympus Monts",
		"choice4":"Olympus Mons",
		"correct":"Olympus Mons on Mars"
	},
	{
		"id":"88",
		"question":"A neutron star is the strongest magnet in the universe.",
		"choice1":"false",
		"choice2":"true",
		"choice3":"maybe",
		"choice4":"neither true nor false",
		"correct":"true"
	},
	{
		"id":"89",
		"question":"The star _____________ is so dense, a handful of it weighs about 454,000 kgs",
		"choice1":"Sirius B",
		"choice2":"Sirius A",
		"choice3":"Sirius C",
		"choice4":"Sirius D",
		"correct":"Sirius B"
	},
	{
		"id":"90",
		"question":"Since Neptune's discovery in _______, it has made just about three-quarters of one revolution around the Sun.",
		"choice1":"1846",
		"choice2":"1847",
		"choice3":"1848",
		"choice4":"1849",
		"correct":"1846"
	},
	{
		"id":"91",
		"question":"Voyager 1 spacecraft is the farthest human-made object in the universe.",
		"choice1":"true",
		"choice2":"false",
		"choice3":"maybe",
		"choice4":"neither the two",
		"correct":"true"
	},
	{
		"id":"92",
		"question":"Due to its size, Pluto's moon ______ is also considered to be a double dwarf planet, rather than a moon orbiting its planet.",
		"choice1":"Charon",
		"choice2":"Caron",
		"choice3":"Carreon",
		"choice4":"Chorn",
		"correct":"Charon"
	},
	{
		"id":"93",
		"question":"The deepest surface point on Mars is ______, about 3 km deep.",
		"choice1":"Hellas",
		"choice2":"Dark Matter",
		"choice3":"Centaurus",
		"choice4":"Hellas D",
		"correct":"Hellas"
	},
	{
		"id":"94",
		"question":"About 1000 Earths would fit inside _______ and the Sun could hold about 1000 Jupiters.",
		"choice1":"Jupiter",
		"choice2":"Mercury",
		"choice3":"Venus",
		"choice4":"Saturn",
		"correct":"Jupiter"
	},
	{
		"id":"95",
		"question":"Even though it is closest to the Sun, _________ has ice in its craters.",
		"choice1":"Earth",
		"choice2":"Mars",
		"choice3":"Jupiter",
		"choice4":"Mercury",
		"correct":"Mercury"
	},
	{
		"id":"96",
		"question":"What is the densest planet in the Solar System.",
		"choice1":"Pluto",
		"choice2":"Mercury",
		"choice3":"Earth",
		"choice4":"Venus",
		"correct":"Earth"
	},
	{
		"id":"97",
		"question":"A ________ is the amount of time it takes the Sun to revolve around the center of the Milky Way, about 225 million years.",
		"choice1":"light year",
		"choice2":"cosmic year",
		"choice3":"space year",
		"choice4":"leap year",
		"correct":"cosmic year"
	},
	{
		"id":"98",
		"question":"A new star is born in our galaxy every ___ days. ",
		"choice1":"16",
		"choice2":"17",
		"choice3":"18",
		"choice4":"19",
		"correct":"18"
	},
	{
		"id":"99",
		"question":"Jupiter's core is non-metal, but due to the immense pressure inside ______, the core has become a metal. This metal is liquid metallic hydrogen.",
		"choice1":"Jupiter",
		"choice2":"Mars",
		"choice3":"Earth",
		"choice4":"Uranus",
		"correct":"Jupiter"
	}
	];
		